Ladies and gentlemen, good evening and a
very warm welcome to the ICICI Lumbard
General Insurance Company Limited's Q4
and FY2026 earnings conference call.
From the senior management, we have with
us today Mr. Sanjiv Mantri, MD and CEO
of the company. Mr. Gopal Balachandran,
CFO,
Mr. Anand Singhi, Chief Retail and
Government. Mr. Serish nayak chief
enterprise AI and technology
Mr. Sep Gurada chief corporate solutions
international and bank insurance Mr.
Gorav Aurora chief commercial lines and
motor underwriting and claims
and Mr. Girishes Seagal chief health UW
and claims customer service and
operations.
Please note that any statements or
comments made in today's call that may
look like forward-looking statements are
based on information presently available
to the management and do not constitute
an indication of any future performance
as the future involves risks and
uncertainties which could cause results
to differ materially from current views
being expressed.
As a reminder, all participants lines
will be in the listenonly mode and there
will be an opportunity for you to ask
questions after the presentation
concludes.
Should you need assistance during this
conference, please signal an operator by
pressing star then zero on your
touchstone port.
Please note that this conference is
being recorded.
I now hand the conference over to Mr.
Sanjie Mantri, MD and CEO ICIC Lumbard
General Insurance Limited. Thank you and
over to you sir.
>> Thank you.
>> Good evening to each one of you. Thank
you for joining the earnings conference
call of ICS Lombard for quarter 4 and
financial year 2026.
I would like to commence with an
overview of the economic and industry
trends which have shaped the operating
environment over past few months coupled
with insights on our company's
performance and our key initiatives.
Following that, our CFO Gopal
Walachandan will take you through the
company's financial performance for
quarter 4 and financial year 2026.
The quarter gone by has been an eventful
one. For the first two months, the
Indian economy exhibited continued
momentum of growth from the previous
quarter. Whereas the month of March 2026
has seen has been unprecedented in terms
of the geopolitical challenges. The
ongoing conflict in West Asia has
heightened global economic uncertaintity
leading to volatility in energy prices
and financial markets. These external
risks could have some spillover effects
on the Indian economy warranting a
measured and watchful approach. That
being said, India's macroeconomic
fundamentals today are considerably
strong and more resilient than in
previous periods of global stress. This
provides a degree of comfort in our
ability to absorb external shocks.
Although we remain mindful of evolving
global conditions,
let me now dwell upon the ensuing
quarter and the year gone by. Retail
sales of private cars, two wheelers and
tractors remained positive for the year.
In accordance with the data reported by
WAN for financial year 2026, the sales
growth of private car and two wheeler
stood at healthy 11.9% and 13.2%
respectively.
Pertinently for H2 2026, the sales
growth of private car and two wheeler
stood at 17.8 and 21.5 as against 4.6
and 3.2 respectively in H1 2026 led by
GST rationalization.
This continued momentum is also seen in
quarter 4 2026 wherein the growth of
private car and two-wheeler stood at a
healthy 16.3 and 24.7% respectively.
Also noteworthy was the fact that two
wheeler sales surpassed surpassed their
their pre-COVID peak and were at a
decadal high.
Even the sales of commercial vehicle
bases the data reported by WAN have
witnessed a growth of 20.2% in H2 2026
versus 14.9%
for H1 2026 and a fullear growth of
12.9%.
Given the early trends of numbers
reported by certain banks, credit growth
is expected to be in double digit for
quarter 4 2026 with broad-based
expansion across segments. Also, vehicle
vehicle financing continued to be an
important contributor to credit growth
broadly in line with the trends observed
in retail automoil sales.
We believe that the above factors
augment well for the industry in time to
come. Moving to the regulatory update.
You may be aware that IRDA has mandated
insurers to prepare and present their
financial statements in accordance with
the applicable Indas effective 1st April
2026. We view we view this as a positive
step as the enhanced disclosure
requirements under India's framework
will meaningfully improve transparency
and align the reporting standards of
Indian insurers with global practices.
While the regulator requires insurers to
provide the reporting as per both India
and Indian GAP for 2027 and 2028, it has
provided the insurer the option of
seeking forbearance to transitioning the
statutory accounting to India for the
first year. We've examined the option
provided by the authority and believe it
would be appropriate to seek the
forbearance in order to ensure that the
transition is executed in a calibrated
and oper operationally robust manner.
Another important initiative announced
by the authority is the public insurance
registry which is expected to become a
key pillar of India's digital public
infrastructure.
As the framework evolves, PIR has the
potential to support industry growth by
improving penetration, driving
efficiency, elevating customer service
and also enabling better risk selection
across ecosystem. We believe that over
time it will also enhance transparency,
strengthen trust and create enduring
benefit for the policy holder, insurers
and the broader financial system.
Let me not dwell upon the industry
performance for the year ended March
31st, 2026.
The general insurance industry reported
a GDPI growth of 9.2% for 2026.
Excluding crop and marel segment, the
gross GDPI growth stood at 13.3% for
2026.
Speaking of the specific segments within
the industry, the commercial segment
reported a growth of 12.2% for 2026.
However, if one was to break down this
growth into H1 and H2, the growth was
14.2 and 9.6% respectively.
As one observes, the business witnessed
elevated level of competitive intensity
and pricing pressure especially in the
fire segment in the second half of the
year leading to muted growth. The
renewals of April 1st 2026 also are
being reported at a discount to the
previous year reflecting that this trend
is likely to continue for quarter 1 2027
as well. On the positive side however we
also would like to mention that the in
the reinsurance renewals for financial
year 2027 have been soft.
The motor segment growth for the
industry stood at 9.2% 2% for financial
year 2026 with the momentum experience
post the GST rationalization the second
half of the year has witnessed improved
growth levels of 10 and a half with the
first half which stood at 7.6%.
The health segment including mass health
grew by 15.4% for 2026 which makes it
the fastest growing segment for last 5
years for from financial year 2022 to
2026.
Within this the group health line of
business view at 12.8% for 2026 whereas
the retail health g growth stood at
19.9% for 2026.
Speaking on the underwriting performance
of the industry overall the combined
ratio of the industry deteriorated from
113.2% in 9 month financial year 2025 to
119.3
in 9 month 2026. The overall combined
ratio for private players remained
relatively flattish for from triple 1.2%
for the period 9 month 2025 to triple
1.5%
for the period 9 month 2026. Due to fing
combined ratio for the motor line of
business continue to remain elevated at
128.1%
for 9 month 2026 with 123.8% for the
period ended 9 month 2025.
I will now proceed to present our
company's performance across key
business segments for 2026. The company
reported a growth of 7% in gross
domestic premium income for 2026
compared to the industry growth of 9.2%
for the same period. ICS Lombard
achieved a growth of 18.2% and 15.7% in
quarter 4 and H2 2026 respectively
against an industry growth of 10.9 and
11.2%. 2% over the same period.
However, excluding the crop and market
segment, the company recorded a growth
of 10.2%
and for financial year 2026 by the
industry view at 13.3% for the same
period.
In the commercial line segment, our
growth stood at 5.4% for financial year
2026 as against compared to industry
growth of 12.2% 2% for 2026.
During H1 2026, a growth in commercial
line stood at 6.5% versus industry
growth of 14.2%.
Bills for H2 2026, the growth level
stood at 3.8%
versus industry growth of 9.6%.
Aid amidst competitive pressure, we
continue to drive profitable growth
through prudent underwriting and
judicious risk selection through our
multi- channelannel distribution. We
continue to maintain leadership position
in liability and marine cargo line of
business for financial year 2026.
In motor segment, our growth stood at
7.6% for financial year 2026. As again
the industry growth of 9.2% for the same
period. In H1 of 2026, we grew at 2.2%
in the motor segment versus the industry
growth which grew at 7.6%.
However, H2 of 2026, we exceeded the
growth level of industry by 1 and a
half% in motor that is 12% with the
industry growth of 10.5%.
This momentum was evident in quarter 4
of financial year 2026 where we achieved
a growth of 15% with while the industry
grew at 10%.
Our portfolio mix for private car,
two-wheer and combined and commercial
vehicles stood at 52.8 25.4 4 and 21.8%
respectively for financial year 2026.
In the health segment for 2026, we grew
by 20% as against the industry growth of
15.4%
on a 1 byN basis.
For quarter 4 2026, the growth stood at
a robust 38.2%
as again the industry growth of 20.5%.
Our retail sales business continue to
demonstrate strong growth of 51.1%
for 2026 significantly outfacing the
industry growth of 19.9% in the same
period.
Consequently, our market share has
improved from 3.3% in financial year
2025 to 4.1% in financial year 2026.
For the year, the company has seen a 2x
growth in the new retail health indeed
business source. Compared to the
previous year, our share of long-term
premiums in new business for retail
health stands at 42.1%
for financial year 2021, up from 28.5%
for financial year 2025. This
performance has been driven by on
ongoing product innovation and sustained
investment in strengthening our real
health distribution franchise or retail
health uh distribution franchise.
For the overall group health portfolio
portfolio, we continue to maintain a
disciplined approach with a focus on
managing the book effectively. The group
health segment recorded a growth of 11%
for financial year 2026 over 2025
with a market share being 8.7% for
financial year 2026.
We have kept a focus on augmenting cash
flows through underlying long-term
business in various lines of business.
Our advanced premium in motor insurance
has increased by over 15% in financial
year 2026 with financial year 2025.
A market share in advanced premium
excluding motor share stands at 12.5%
for financial year 2026 up from 9.6%
from financial year 2025.
Our discipent focus on profitable growth
has helped us deliver consistent
outcomes over time with market
fluctuations may impact performance in
individual quarters. Our track record
reflects our ability to navigate cycles
and deliver value over the long term. If
we analyze the 10-year time horizon from
financial year 2020 2016 to 2025, it is
pertinent to note that the company's
average combined ratio stood at 102.9%
reflecting sustained underwriting
discipline across various market
conditions. This would compare favor
favorably with the industry average of
115.3%
over the same period.
Furthermore, our investment performance
has also remained strong. Over the same
10 year uh 10-year horizon, we delivered
a robust average realized yield of 8.7%
supported by prudent assent asset
allocation and effective capital
management over multiple cycles. This in
turn has translated into an healthy
average return on equity of 19.1% over
the 10-year period, which would compare
favorably against the industry average
ROE of 4%.
Reinforcing the strength and resilience
of our overall business model and
consistency of our execution.
Our one and one team philosophy
continues to foster collaboration and
operational excellence
enabling a unified approach across the
organization.
As a part of this philosophy, we'll now
apprise you of certain key initiatives.
First, I would like to highlight a
strategic capability we have built in
house. one that materially strengthens
our execution engine. We call it IL1
Force.
IL1 Force is an enterprise productivity
platform which has been in operation for
over a year and is used by over 10,000
sales employees. It is on track to
become the single operating platform for
all our 15,000 employees across the
organization. IL14 integrates work
execution, performance management,
collaboration and recognition into a
single platform, simplifying operations,
reinforcing execution, discipline, and
driving accountability with real time
enterprise wide visibility.
The platform enables structured partner
engagement, task management, and
real-time performance analytics across
the partner life cycle. Its renewal
capability has improved conversion by 5%
while enhanced engagement with while
enhanced engagement has doubled partner
participation and expanded market reach.
Notably in health indemnity improved
engagement led to a 2x increase in agent
activation and a doubling of new retail
business.
Our is picture app, a one-stop solution
for insurance and wellness needs,
achieved 21 million downloads as of 31st
March 2026, reflecting the growing
customer engagement and digital
adoption. The GWP earned from the
Takeare app during the period 2026 was
51 5170 million with the corresponding
premium earning for 2025 which stood at
2237.2
million from a claim intimation
perspective. 67% of the customers now
intimate their health reimbursement
claims through the app while 82% of the
claim intimation of a travel product
trip seccure plus went through take care
app. We will continue to focus on
improving the service experience of our
customers with a single simplified
interface for their insurance
requirements. We continue to improve our
efficiency level in motor claims too.
Our preferred partner network service
75.5% of our nonoem claims for quarter 4
2026 respectively up from 74.1% for
quarter 4 2025. For 9 months we recorded
an NPS of 69 for motor claims.
In the retail segment 98.8% of our total
claims were paid within 30 days for
financial year 2026. For the 9 month
2026 on a count basis the number stood
at 99.9%
with the corresponding number from the
industry being at 82.1%.
For Ryan month 2026 we recorded an NPS
of 73 for health claims demonstrating
strong satisfaction level and
reinforcing our position as a
customercentric organization.
A health sahab has further strengthened
our onground claim supports for our
health customers and our customer
coverage improving by 25% over the
previous year. As a part of their
feedback, 95% of our customer survey
rated their experience as exemplary
highlighting the support provided during
claims processing and assistance with
hospital coordination. This VAMS are
focused on best-in-class service to our
customers during the moment that truly
matters.
The one call center initiative continues
to deliver strong momentum in the
company's transition toward the digital
first do-it-yourself service model. In
March 2026, more than five lakh service
engagements, 69% of the total service
engagements were executed digitally. Our
differentiated service initiatives which
we have spoken about in previous
earnings call have resulted in increase
of our call center NPS to 74 in quarter
4 2026 from 60 in quarter 1 2026.
Before I close the current year marks an
important milestone in the journey of
ICLI Lombard. As we enter into our 25th
year of operations, we would like to
take this opportunity to express our
heartfelt gratitude to all our stake
stakeholders who have been truly who has
truly supported us in our journey so far
and we look forward to your continued
trust, encouragement and support in the
years ahead. I will now request Gupal to
take you through the financial numbers
for quarter 4 and financial year 2026.
Thanks Anjie and uh good evening to each
one of you. I will now give you a brief
overview of the financial performance of
the recently concluded quarter in the
full financial year. We have uploaded
the results presentation on our website.
You can access it as we walk you through
the performance numbers with effect from
October 1, 2024. Long-term products are
accounted on a 1 byN basis as mandated
by the regulator IID. Please refer our
investor presentation slide number 16
for the further details on comparison of
financials on a on an n and 1 byn basis.
It may be noted that all the numbers
that I will be speaking about are on a 1
byn basis unless otherwise mentioned.
On combined ratio our combined ratio on
an n basis for fi26 was 102.4%.
As against 102.6% 6% in FI25.
Our command ratio on a 1 byN basis for
the current year was 103.4 as against
102.8% in FI25.
Excluding the impact of wage code of
rupees.55 billion. The combined ratio
for FI26 stood at 102.1%.
And 103.1%
on a N basis and 1 by N basis
respectively. Our combined ratio on a n
basis for quarter 4 was 100.5
as against 102.1 in quarter 4 of fi25.
Our combined ratio on a 1 by n basis for
quarter 4 current year was 101.2
as against 102.5 in quarter 4 of last
year. On the investments, our investment
assets during the quarter rose to rups
584.21 21 billion as at March 31, 2026,
up from rupes 582.96 billion as at
December 31, 2025.
Our investment leverage net of
borrowings was at 3.48 times at March
31, 2026
and at 3.6 times as at December 31,
2025. Investment income was at rupees
47.42 billion in FI26 as against rupees
42.5 billion in FI25.
On a quarterly basis, investment income
was at rupees 9.85 billion in Q4 this
year as against rupes 8.77 billion in Q4
last year. During the quarter under
review, the company has recognized we
have a policy on impairment of uh
investment assets. Uh basis that the
company has recognized an impairment on
its equity portfolio investments of
rupees.49
49 billion in this quarter for FI26
versus a small ride back that we had of
almost about 3 crores uh that we had in
quarter 4 of uh the last financial year
driven by the prevailing market
correction. Now coming to profitability
our profit before tax grew by 10.2% to
rupes 36.59 billion in FI26 as against
rupes 33.21 21 billion in FI25
excluding the impact of the wage code
that I referred earlier of rupees.55
billion the PBT grew by 11.8% to rupees
37.14 billion in FI26
our PBT grew by 7.5% to rupees 7.18
billion in Q4 FI26 as against rupees
6.68 68 billion in Q4 FI25 on the profit
after tax. Therefore, consequently on a
1 byN basis, the PAD grew by 10.5% to
rupees 27.72 billion in FI26 as against
rupees 25.08 billion in FI25.
Again excluding the impact of the wage
code, the PAT on a 1 byN basis grew by
12.2% to rupees 28.14 billion in FI26.
On an end basis, PAD grew by 14.1% to
rupees 27.61 billion in FI26 as against
rupees 24.19 billion in FI25.
On an end basis, excluding the impact of
the wage code, the PAD grew by 15.9% to
rupees 28.03 billion in FI26.
Our PAD on a 1 byN basis grew by 7.3% to
5.47 billion in Q4 this year as against
rupees 5.1 billion in Q4 last year. same
numbers on an end basis PAD grew by
15.6% to to rupees 5.39 billion in Q4
FI26 as against 4.66 billion in Q4 FI25
coming to return on average or ROE was
17.8% 8% in FI26 as against 19.1% in
FI25
excluding the impact of wage code of
rupees.55 billion ROE stood at 18.1%
for FI26
ROE for quarter 4 current year was at
13.3%
as again 14.5% in Q4 FI25
coming to dividend the board of
directors of the company has proposed a
final dividend of seven per share for
FI26 this payment is however subject to
approval of share shareholders in the
encing general annual general meeting of
the company. The overall dividend for
FI26 including the above proposed final
dividend is rupes 13.5 per share. Last
year the overall dividend was rupes 12.5
per share. On solveny we continue to
exhibit a very healthy solveny ratio of
2.67 times at March 31st 2026 as against
2.69 69 at December 31, 2025, which
continues to be higher than the minimum
regulatory requirement. The solvency of
course was impacted by roughly about 14
basis points as an outcome of the
marktomarket loss position that we had
on the equity book as at March 31, 2026.
As I conclude, I would like to state
that we are aligned with our ethos of
driving profitable growth, consistent
and sustainable value creation for all
our stakeholders while ensuring that the
interest of policy holders are at the
forefront at all times. I would like to
thank you all for attending this
earnings call and we will now be happy
to take questions that you may have.
Thank you.
>> Thank you very much. We will now begin
the question and answer session. Anyone
who wishes to ask a question may press
star and one on their touchtone
telephone. If you wish to remove
yourself from the question queue, you
may press star and two. Participants are
requested to please use handsets while
asking a question. Ladies and gentlemen,
we will now wait for a moment while the
question queue assembles.
Our first question comes from the line
of Supraim Data from Jeff. Please go
ahead.
Hello. Um, thanks a lot for the
opportunity. My first question is on the
competitive environment in industry. Uh,
there have been articles recently
indicating that competition in the
commercial lines have been fairly
elevated. You indicated that you know
the motoral lines combined ratio remains
elevated. So if you could give us an
idea about you know how competitive
environment in the different segments is
panning out that would be helpful and is
there any improvement due to now uh the
EUM guidelines kicking in. So that's my
first question. The second question
coming to the loss ratio side uh this
year fourth quarter motor TP loss ratio
has been significantly lower than what
we have seen in the last uh years in uh
fourth quarter motor TP loss ratio. So
just wanted to understand you know what
has played out for this uh significant
improvement versus the run rate that we
have seen previously and why is the crop
loss ratio negative if you could give
some color on that. Lastly on FRS papal
you know would it be possible for you to
give us some understanding or clarity
regarding you know how your PAT under
IFRS would look versus the IGAP pat um
that would be very helpful. Thank you.
Can you take the second one first?
>> Maybe I can take the second and the
third and then maybe I can ask maybe
Sanjiv can respond the first one. Um I
think on the loss ratio of Supraim I
think uh this obviously comes to us
every quarter and I think our response
will still remain the same as in to say
that one you have to keep looking at
motor as a category as compared to one
looking at separately uh motor own
damage and third party. That's one.
Second, I think we would continue to
again request all of you to keep looking
at numbers more on uh full year basis as
compared to let's say any given quarter.
And uh just to kind of refresh what we
have been telling the street is I think
the range that we're comfortable on
motor is between 65 to 67. I think that
is the range that we have maintained and
if you have seen for the full year
current year I think we ended at roughly
about 66.3%.
it's well within that range and hence to
that extent I think that's the range
that we would be kind of tracking pretty
closely. Uh so in that sense there is
nothing that has kind of changed. Uh if
you ask us has has any of our reserving
philosophy undergone a change the short
answer is no and we continue to kind of
maintain prudence uh in terms of
maintaining our uh loss reserves. So
hence uh I think we have to keep looking
at numbers more on full year basis as
compared to any given quarters. So
that's one crop. Uh I think again uh
time and again we have kind of talked
about it because generally again just to
kind of refresh most of the businesses
in crop get booked around quarter 2 and
somewhere around quarter 3 and maybe
early quarter 4 because those are
typically the two seasons that largely
get exhibited. In our case, we had
predominantly large exposure on crop
largely from one state of which a large
part of our premium was something that
had got kind of booked roughly around
quarter two of the year and as we have
said it obviously takes time for the
season to kind of play out in terms of
actual loss experiences and in any in
any quarter when you see that experience
play out then to that extent obviously
and if you recollect even at the time of
booking the uh policies we obviously
follow a very very conservative approach
of providing for almost 100% % loss
ratio at the time of writing the risk
and as the actual experiences play out
obviously to that extent in case if you
see some kind of a positive change then
to that extent that gets reflected again
in the given uh quarter and hence to
that extent is why possibly you are
seeing that number uh in line with the
loss ratio outcomes for quarter 4 here
again I would continue to urge that you
should again look at the numbers more on
a full year basis on a fular basis is
pretty much kind of range bound whether
you look at fi25 or whether whether you
look at FI26
um on India's I think uh uh in line with
what we had also kind of put out as a
part of the opening uh transcript um at
this point of time uh given the state at
uh which uh so one if you ask us is the
now now that is now there is a
definitive uh uh date uh in so far as uh
transitioning to India is concerned so
hence that's a very very welcome step in
so far as the overall uh industry is
concerned I think that's what rightfully
so the regulator has done
Um in terms of uh uh our own transition,
I think we do have uh we have been
working on a plan of action in terms of
getting our uh processes internally uh
up and ready so that we are able to kind
of start reporting uh numbers to all of
you uh uh whenever we are kind of ready
for it. Um at this point of time I think
we will continue to kind of give uh in
line with what we have done even in the
past we have been submitting performer
numbers uh for the last two years. So we
will continue even for 26 27 on a
quarterly basis in line with the
requirements we will continue to submit
uh India India's based results to the
regulator and maybe we will come back to
all of you at an appropriate time uh and
then we will possibly start talking
about more specifics in terms of the
impact that it does on both uh the
combined ratios and maybe the return on
equity objectives because those are the
two two things that the market obviously
kind of wants to hear from us. So we
will come back on that uh and maybe on
the first point.
>> So also you know from the just to close
out the FRS part and we've always said
in the past also that uh the year of
adoption there would be a significant
decline combined ratio. It can be in the
range of 300 basis to you know maybe 400
450 basis point. But look that's only
the accounting part of it. economic
value over a period of time it is
expected to converge and have the same
uh you know uh value creation for the
company as it happens. So so our stance
pretty much remains same and yes from
next quarter one we would end up doing
our submissions on that count. Uh with
respect to super on the competitive
pressure that is there and we spoke
about that also when we were giving the
overall briefing for the year that has
gone by. Yes, it has intensified on
commercial and business. Uh at the same
time, the the capacity overall on the
reinsurance side was very high available
and we've been able to see to some
extent it getting negated. Uh will this
continue? My my own belief is market
forces will play out but our own
understanding is when we see intensive
competition the selection has to get
sharper. Uh because it's will we compete
in the market? Answer is yes. uh but uh
what we've been able to write and what
we will write we will be creating
differentiation if you remember last
year even in you know over quarters we
had said that there was a marginal loss
of uh market share for us on the fire
side purely was on account of the fact
that uh we will do what is comfortable
and the output is in some ways here to
see these are all very exposure-driven
products and you have to be cautious of
what you pick and what you don't and
we'll continue to follow that uh there
is no overarching worry. We are very
well placed as an institution in terms
of what practices we have to counter any
such measures that come up in the market
and overall insurance general insurance
in particular have seen uh these kind of
conduct at multiple levels and we are
well pleased about it on motor also in a
similar vein uh yes the industry is been
uh stretched at multiple counts the
command ratio which I just spoke about
for the 9 months stays at 128 clearly
not a workable one We continue to pick
and choose uh and deliver uh uh a result
which is differentiated from the market.
It's purely led by on multiple count
distribution and underwriting practices
which differentiates in own damage as
well as third party with briefly you
know uh Gopal spoke about. Thank you.
>> Understood perfectly clearly. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thanks.
>> Thank you. Our next question comes from
the line of Pra Jen from Motila Losal.
Please go ahead.
>> Yeah. Hi everyone. Uh few questions from
my side. Firstly, if I just wanted to
take a view on your solvency which is
like uh pretty high at 2.7. How do you
think that you will uh whether you
because you've been generating good
profits over the past few years and in
fact from FI22 to FI25
and even now the solveny has been
increasing. So how do you see you know
whether you can utilize the solvency
better in terms of paying out dividends
or in any other form or to kind of
because and unless the growth is really
exceptional we I'm sure that we wouldn't
need that kind of excess solveny on the
balance sheet that's question number one
second you know we've been talking about
motor TP price hike and uh you know
we've discussed this in the last call
last few calls as well but given the
trajectory on the motor TP loss ratios
at about 63 3.2 in FI25 and 63.8 this
year for you. Do you think that uh you
know motor DP price hike can uh come in?
Um and my last question is on on the
health insurance front. Uh uh Gopal if
you could split up the loss ratios for
retail retail and group.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So maybe Yeah. Uh so uh so
pre uh uh so the first one I think uh um
I think as a company uh what we have
always maintained is uh uh sufficient uh
margins when it comes to solvency
because uh in uh the Indian market is
still on solveny one regulation I think
of course there is a road map to maybe
eventually transition to risk based
capital which again as what as what the
regulator has rightfully done on India
I'm
uh they would possibly try and do a
similar thing even on transition to risk
based capital as well. So obviously one
will have to wait and see how that plays
out but till that point of time I think
the Indian market continues to be guided
by solvency one uh which uh as I said
still mandates uh capital ask to be
maintained bases the gross exposures
that you have as an entity and hence to
that extent we have to be uh mindful of
and prudent uh in terms of the levels of
solveny that we carry as an institution.
Um having said that I think uh to your
point on uh the last few years I think
uh fair observation but if you see I
think last couple of years in specific I
think we have been relatively uh lower
uh when it comes when it comes to growth
but that's something that we have
already seen a clear positive uh
reversal of trends emerging for us and
with the momentum that that we have kind
of seen in all fairness one would
obviously want to kind of make sure that
we are able to kind of get it extended
uh even as we head into FI27 and the
moment you will see as what you have
seen uh let's say even uh in the second
half of this year growth kind of coming
back uh so to that extent obviously one
will uh look at consuming some part of
uh the solveny that we have and three
ours solveny is also guided by obviously
a mix of what is it that we want to
drive in terms of the growth objective
and two at the same time make sure that
we are kind of appropriately kind of
rewarding uh the investors who have kind
of obviously placed faith in us and in
that context I think if you would have
seen historically we do have a board
governed uh dividend distribution policy
in place uh on an average I think what
we have been able to kind of distribute
uh is roughly about uh 25% of our PAT
and this year again as what we had kind
of put out in our opening transcript
roughly about 13 and a half rupees per
share for the full year roughly
translates to almost about 25% of for
profit after tax. Uh so hence it's
obviously will be a continued
combination of both uh rewarding the
shareholders appropriately and at the
same time making sure that we are able
to use the capital for uh growth. And
the three the third part as I said we
will obviously kind of keep a watch on
the transition to risk based capital. So
that's one uh to your point on the
breakup for the health loss ratio
numbers I think yeah thankfully this
time the question has come ahead of time
so so maybe we'll answer it. Uh so I
think uh Q4 of last year this right now
I'll give you the numbers for quarter 4
employer employee book uh the last last
year Q4 the loss ratio was uh 98% and
this year that number is almost the same
at 981%.
On the retail uh indemnity book uh the
loss ratio for Q4 last year was 64.8
and this year quarter 4 the loss ratio
on the indemnity book is at 57.6.
Now the same year numbers on a full year
basis employer employee book for last
year has been at 97.2
and this year full year the employer
employee book loss ratio stands at about
91.9
on the retail indemnity full year last
year was 67.9
this year full year is at about 64.6 six
uh so just therefore now to kind of
summit again on the indemnity book I
think the range that we have spoken
about is between 65 to 70% and that's
what we have been kind we've been kind
of largely talking through even in the
past several quarters and broadly if you
see the experience that one has seen the
good part is I think one we have been
able to book build a book uh which is
pretty much to our liking and it has
kind of played out both in terms of
growth in market share and also staying
within the loss ratio range so those are
the responses to the two questions maybe
the motor third party.
>> So uh yes uh I think uh possibly it's
been almost 5 years now since the uh
industry has uh got a hike uh and the
loss ratio at the industry level as far
as motor TP is concerned is at around 85
and thereabouts. uh which is
significantly you know elevated uh where
we are we have been able to uh if you
see and Gopal briefly spoke about it we
had to also reconfigure our portfolio to
get aligned and drive the efficiency uh
which we've been able to reflect uh it
does at time lead to a loss and whenever
we end up having discussions uh whether
individually or collectively there's so
much of you know questioning as to why
has the market share gone gone up that
is what it takes to reconfigure. Uh
we've also recalibrated our practice in
terms of ground surveillance and doing
what is required uh to avoid fraud which
probably we would easily say is among
the lowest in the industry. There's no
way we can claim to eliminate it. So
there are multiple factors that go about
it. We remain desirous of the fact that
yes the TP hike for the industry is
overdue and uh sooner than later that
should play out. uh but we can only
control what is in in our hand. This one
definitely is not and in line with that
we continue to forge our own uh
understanding and deliberation to
penetrate market at multiple counts and
make it work for us uh as a company and
uh from an industry standpoint sooner
than later we do hope the relief comes
through.
>> Thank you. Thank you so much.
>> Thank you.
>> Thanks.
Thank you.
Our next question comes from the line of
Sankit Koda from Aendis Spark. Please go
ahead.
>> Uh yeah, thank you. Thank you for the
opportunity. Uh so so my my my first
question is is that last year we we kind
of lost market share in commercial lines
um and um and given given the market is
soft as you highlighted. uh is it safe
to say that uh we we will claw back kind
of a market share in the software market
or we will remain as cautious as we were
last time and and and in and and in in
in these lines just wanted to understand
given given the soft market growth
outlook uh given given um your second
half growth is 16%age
uh and maybe crop being a new tendering
uh uh tendering uh year uh how do you
see growth of the 16 percentage to
continue for the next here uh and any
any color if you can give on that those
lines will be very useful that that's my
first question maybe maybe I will ask
another one later
>> okay sit I think uh last year uh I'm
saying when you're saying last year it's
a year before the one which you just
given the result which is financial 25
we were we didn't lose market share we
had gained by 0.1 we had a quarter here
where we missed but overall we had
gained we talking about a market share
which is in the range of 13.7 which was
year before last this year we have
closed by8 7 basis point lower uh and
it's driven through multiple
configuration when we meet up personally
for I more than happy to sit run through
that uh these with that kind of a share
that we draw these fluctuations to
ensure that we select right can happen
uh but uh the commercial practice that
we have is very unique uh in the
industry and it's not driven by what
business we are able to write it's about
how we are able to even manage claims
uh there's a significant contribution on
large corporates to mid and to small.
Honestly speaking from an entity
standpoint we have been we have done a
much more uh uh you know recent job on
the large corporate side and over last
two to three years which we have been
briefing to you it's been a more
distributionled growth and we've been
able to diversify our port our portfolio
in a in a significant manner. We do we
do believe that uh we are we have a very
significant edge in the overall practice
and we will be able to uh have a you
know a reasonable presence as far as
commercial is concerned. I don't want to
jump the gun to say uh where the market
share will be but we will be a very
relevant player and it's not uh easy to
see us losing foothold on that on an
overarching basis. crop coming into
play. We will uh and yes the market
opens up significantly. We are still
awaiting the details in terms of on what
contours this market will open as and
when those guidelines come in. uh we
will be able to comment as to what it is
but we've always maintained our stand
that crop will be purely on selection
basis of what we feel is appropriate
rather than a targeted segment where
we'll say
no that's not the way we look at it do
we want to participate it's a bold yes
do we want to you know chase it the
answer is no uh we we very well placed
overall uh to and we excited actually in
terms So the opportunity that will
present itself our current crop number
user is what was there year before last
or this year virtually half and uh uh
there is some play available for us to
make it count in this year.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Sorry.
>> Oh, sorry. You're saying something. Go
ahead. Please go ahead.
>> No, no, no. Sorry. Sorry. When I meant
uh April last year, you lost market
share in commercial lines because you
believed the market was too soft and and
if you are assuming it is too soft again
maybe maybe full year you caught it up
but but but given April is very strong
in the renewal for for uh fire whether
whether whether whether whether it will
have any implication in one growth or or
April growth which is which is
significantly very big and and lastly
yeah go ahead lastly on crop crop just
just wanted to add is that uh whether
whether you confined till till last
three years to to one state u maybe I I
don't know what final controls will be
but but it is fair to say that you you
will be expanding beyond a particular
state in in in the current year or not
broadly broadly that's that's way you
are strategically thinking in those
lines or not is the point I wanted to
check
>> yeah yeah so so one state uh worked out
because it was a line of what we wanted
to do it is not a plan that will
continue to be a one state p this we
will go uh wherever it makes uh you know
uh uh commercial sense and we believe
that it is appropriate and crop
obviously can play out the way it is. We
are still awaiting structure. So there
is there is we are open to uh whatever
that comes up our way to be very honest
on that point and on the commercial part
in terms of uh uh what you were saying
look the growth of the industry itself
will get impacted and we are we are a
sub we are an offshoot of that. So uh uh
we can do better, we can do worse
depending on how it pans out. Uh uh but
overall if you remember in H1 uh we had
a
uh much bigger loss with what happened
in H2. So uh we've also done what is
required uh so what cannot get you know
what cannot be acquired through uh large
corporates we have played out in
distribution has taken its own play but
we are very well entrenched. So we
should be fine on the commercial part
also overall as an entity
>> and and if a growth point of view given
sorry to interrupt we request you to
please the growth on commercial because
of fire being there the industry itself
may have challenges on growth uh let me
uh put this very clearly uh but it
doesn't mean that uh it put us at a
significant disadvantage with anybody
else it would be probably single digit
>> sorry just to squeeze I was asking that
second half our growth was 16%age though
will be weak in first half. So this 16%
growth run rate uh you expect to
continue largely for 527
>> there is so much happening all around
that uh uh how do we predict that but
yes Gopal mentioned that very briefly
we're very confident of moving into the
quarter one and quarter two on a
positive note overall as things stand
yes we but how does the industry play
out overall uh we will have to watch at
that uh we also presume that the the the
tailwinds which got huge number of GST
cuts which led to a very robust quarter
4 uh would continue to play out
definitely will be well placed for a
growth. We we are excited with that
opportunity but we'll have to wait in
terms of how the market plays out. Yeah.
Thank you.
>> Okay. Yeah. Thanks. Yes.
>> Thank you.
Our next question comes from the line of
Nidesh from Invest. Please go ahead.
Thanks for the opportunity sir. My
question is in motor. So in motor in H1
we view lesser than the market. In H2 we
view faster than the market. So what
drove that and what is the outlook of
our growth with industry growth in FI27
on in the motor segment.
>> Yeah. Okay. So D I think uh yes S2 was
better. There was also uh a significant
play that came out on account of new
sales uh for the country doing better
and uh there is no denial in you know
there's nothing which we can say uh that
we tend to do better when new sales are
uh very high and we have seen that new
grew at almost 18.8%
uh for us with 13.4 on the old side. So
on the outlook of financial year 27 um
we'll have to see we do expect a higher
singledigit growth at the industry level
and if that happens it would be again uh
good for us and other thing which worked
out last year was the growth of two
biller by when I was talking I said that
it was at a decadal high in terms of the
overall growth that happened we for last
three four years we have been saying
that we've not beaten the precoid number
on two billers that itself is again a
big plus uh overall on the uh motor
side. I think the only thing I'll just
add this just to what Sanji was saying I
think one of the thing initiatives that
we have also been speaking in our
earlier calls is our relentless focus on
improving retentions
uh and uh we will be very again happy to
kind of uh indicate that uh for the full
year I think at an aggregate let's say
company level a large part of which will
be predominantly let's say retail
business lines I think we have seen an
improvement in our overall retention
numbers go up by almost about 5
percentage points
U so hence that is something that we
will continue to stay focused on even as
we head into FI27. So that will be an
important lever uh that we would
obviously kind of uh uh work on uh
beyond of course the point that Sanjay
made in so far as new vehicle sales is
concerned.
So basically the growth acceleration
that we have seen is a function of
growth new vehicle sales going up
>> new as well as old competitive intensity
reducing and we gaining market share on
a lack to basis. uh so yeah so new and
old and I think it reached sometime in
quarter one last year that we had uh as
a company extensively worked on the
retention part a lot of work was done on
multiple counts uh by us and that's what
Gopal is referring to when he's saying
that we had a delta of higher retention
of our customers
>> sure so and that so should we expect Q
H2 trend to play out next year also that
we will grow faster than the industry or
>> uh our I think I think let me put it
this way we we will we are well placed
overall but uh there are multiple
factors see I mean if there is a there
is a challenge on the energy if the uh
if uh the Indian mentality moves into
the saving part of it rather than
spending the motor sales or auto sales
which probably all of you are well aware
of it actually ends up getting really
muted we'll have to see how that part
comes in uh but we would say that uh the
momentum on quarter 3 to quarter four
and so effectively in quarter one should
play out uh I would say yes we are going
with a very positive mindset at this
point of time
>> sure s sure uh that's it for myself
>> thanks thank thanks
>> thank you our next question comes from
the line of Ain Singh with MK Global go
ahead
>> yeah hi uh thanks for the opportunity uh
good evening a couple of question the
first one uh a bit I would uh say if you
can uh clarify my understanding this 49
cr kind of a charge that you have taken
for diminish in value of investment uh
provisions in this quarter is it largely
driven by the equity market fall or bond
or kind of a both so that's one and
second in motor TP of course you have
explained a lot of things uh my question
is that okay we have not seen a sort of
a price hike but what I change for you
that you have kind of accelerated your
growth in CV segment. Now typically from
whatever we hear it is a CV by and large
where the price revision is required and
it's not so profitable but in Q4 uh it
seems that you have gone a lot higher in
terms of you know uh that CV so what had
changed there what kind of a strategy
there and for the full year around 780
crores of motor third party reserve will
get uh is that number I'm seeing
correctly thanks
>> the last one
>> so maybe I can take the last one uh So
Ainach again again we will keep saying
uh you should keep looking at the loss
ratio range that we have spoken about
for motor as a category which is between
65 to 67 an absolute amount of uh
reserve number that you spoke about
honestly
uh in our sense is something that would
not necessarily be a right metric to
kind of track. A better metric will be
to keep looking at the loss ratio
outcome which is the range that we have
kind of spoken about between 65 to 67.
Now the good part is I think uh I think
what has worked for us I think is I
think we have seen a clear rebound of
growth and at the same time we have been
able to maintain the loss ratio
expectations that we have set out. Uh so
hence to that extent I think uh is where
we have been able to deliver both on
growth as well as in so far as the loss
outcomes and that's something that we
are very very happy with and we are very
very positive uh when we kind of head
into uh FI 27. Um and as I said uh in
response to the earlier question is
there any change in the thought process
of any of our reserving philosophies of
reserving processes? Absolutely no. We
continue to maintain prudence. We
continue to maintain margins uh for any
levels of uncertaintity that we see in
any of the books and more so in the
context of motor third party which has
got a longtail uh uh longtail periods of
loss development. So hence to that
extent uh that's in response to the
point on motor third party. uh to your
first point uh or to to the on the first
question with respect to the 49
crination in the value of investments. I
think this is what I kind of uh
mentioned even as a part of the opening
uh transcript. Uh we have a policy on
impairment of investments uh that we
kind of have in the context of uh equity
investment specifically and consequent
to what we have seen the market
conditions getting exhibited in quarter
four of this year. We have obviously
valuated stocks that we hold and bases
the policy that we have we have done an
impairment of about 49 crores. All of
this 49 crores is in with respect to the
policy on dimination in the value of
equity investments.
>> Yeah. Okay. So now the uh CV growth I
think you're absolutely right. Uh it's
done better but there are you know
multiple moving parts. I don't want to
get into details. We can do it probably
when we meet a vinach uh and talk about
it. uh we've done better but the overall
contribution of CV to the book has still
been range more at 22%.
uh you see multiple you know things and
there's one more aspect that's the cost
of acquisition that comes into play and
if we see moderation we see an
opportunity we are also scanning the
market adding new vectors and something
looks viable we end up doing it we've
also created a significant edge with the
market through a fleet management system
which we are working for last almost uh
you know 18 to 24 months and that has
also started giving us some bit of an
advantage uh as to what we can do with
commercial vehicles Well, it's it's
overarching it's still come rangebound
and we do believe that the overall
growth in CV market also for a2 was at a
reasonable level which I have given in
the numbers in the details which also
again presented us with an opportunity
to do what is required. uh overall on
the practice side if you see where ICS
Lumbard is certainly private car and
two-heer is uh our you know our strength
but CV we continue to uh exhibit uh a
lot more intensity but the outcome used
to be moderate uh for us and for last uh
couple of quarters it's come into play
and I sincerely hope that we'll have a
similar trend going forward next year or
this year rather
Thank you. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Our next question comes from
the line of Nishan Chawat from Kota.
Please go ahead.
>> Hi. Uh this is slightly open-ended. uh
uh the regulator is uh you know looking
at uh uh you know newer set of
guidelines on commissions uh you know
probably capping commissions or
deferring them uh you know assuming that
you know this kind of leads to some
amount of tightening how do you see this
impact on the industry and for yourself
I think we've always maintained you know
uh an an environment with uh where the
regulator enforces it in the past also
we have said that there are quite a few
players who have sought dispensation or
have not followed the guideline and that
does not occur well. Any tightening on a
uniform basis across the industry uh
would place ICSL at a significant
advantage uh uh because we've remained
within the limits of expense of
management and uh if others fall in
place we can only see uh better time
ahead for us as an industry. the the
only thing that remains is uh it should
be practiced across the industry at a
uniform bas on a uniform basis
>> and it's a welcome sign uh if it comes
out uh we always also mention the fact
that we believe the expense of
management should be on a single slab
basis uh so that there's clarity of
execution and let the market forces
decide as to what works for each one of
them in every single business line.
So, so what is the latest in terms of uh
you know regulatory engagement on EOM?
Is there any revision expected around
the corner along with this separately?
>> We can we can only say that whatever is
accessed by each one of you is what we
access and the we await for what the
regulator has in mind. We don't want to
do any second guessing but uh any
tightening on account of that would be
welcomed by us because it puts the
industry in uh good path with respect to
policy holder and also for us as an
institution.
>> Got it. Got it. Thank you very much and
all the best.
>> Thank you.
>> Ladies and gentlemen, we will take that
as a last question for today. I would
now like to hand the conference over to
Mr. Sanjiv Mantri for closing comments.
Over to you sir.
>> Thank you so much for joining in. Uh we
look forward to the new financial
renewed hope. We've definitely as a team
uh been excited as to how we've been
able to close H2 over H1 and more so Q4
over the rest of it. uh we are positive
in terms of how things can work out for
general insurance industry at large and
with the reforms that the regulator has
put in place. Uh but at the same time we
hope that the the world moves to a in a
in a much more you know peaceful manner
in times to come. So thank you so much
and all the best to each one of you for
joining and thank you so much.
>> Thank you.
Thank you. On behalf of ICIC Lumbard
General Insurance Company Limited, that
concludes this conference. Thank you all
for joining us. You may now disconnect
your lines.